



# Lorraine L. Wilson

Attorney

Lorraine Wilson advises and represents school district clients on a wide spectrum of issues with an emphasis on collective bargaining and human resources concerns. Lorraine also has extensive administrative and policy experience at both the statewide and local level.

### **CONTACT**

Tel (206) 622-0203 Fax (206) 223-2003 Cell (253) 209-0409 lorraine@pfrwa.com

## PROFESSIONAL POSITIONS

Attorney, Porter Foster Rorick, 2013-present

Assistant Superintendent Human Resources, Puyallup School District, 2008-2013

Director of Labor and Legislative Relations, Tacoma Public Schools, 2003-2008

Associate Executive Director, Washington State School Directors' Association, 1990-2003

Assistant City Attorney and General Practice, Centralia, Washington, 1989-1990

Legislative Session Attorney, Association of Washington Business, 1989-1990

Associate Attorney, John Biggs Law Office, 1988

## **EDUCATION**

Duke University School of Law, Durham, North Carolina, J.D., with honors, 1987

Reed College, Portland, Oregon, B.A., Political Science, 1984
Phi Beta Kappa and Three Faculty Commendations for Academic Excellence

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Employee Relations and Negotiations Network, Board Member Washington Council of School Attorneys, Past President Washington Association of School Administrators, Past Board Member Sno-King Negotiators

### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Employee discipline and discharge
- Labor and employment
- Public records

- School administration
- Business services & transactions

## SELECTED PRESENTATIONS AND PUBLICATIONS

Washington State School Directors' Association School Law Conference, 2020.

Washington School Personnel Association Legislative Briefing Conference, 2019-2020.

Washington School Personnel Association Annual Conference, 2020.

Washington School Personnel Association Legislative Briefing Conference, 2019.

Washington School Personnel Association/Washington Schools Risk Management Pool School Law Conference, 2011-2019.

Employee Relations and Negotiations Network Workshops, 2018-2021.

Washington Council of School Attorneys, May 2018.

University of Washington School Law Academy, 1997, 2000 and 2003.

Oxford England Roundtable: Public School Law, 2000.

National School Boards Association Conference, 1999.

Targeting Student Learning: The School Board's Role as Policymaker, Co-Author, 1998.